Finding Aid for Mackinac Bridge Authority records, 1950-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Mackinac Bridge Authority records 1950-1967
Mackinac Bridge Authority (Mich.)
3 linear feet
851858 Ca.4b 2
Correspondence, minutes of meetings, reports, and financial statements relating to the planning, financing, building, and operation of the Mackinac Bridge that joins the Lower and Upper Peninsulas of Michigan.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by George Osborn (donor no. 3146 ).
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Mackinac Bridge Authority was established in 1950 with the purpose of determining "the physical and financial feasibility of a bridge connecting the Upper and Lower Peninsulas of Michigan." The authority was furthered empowered in 1952 to finance, build and operate such a bridge. Construction was begun in July 1954 and opened to traffic on November 1, 1957.
These records were accumulated by George Osborn who served as a member of the Mackinac Bridge Authority in the period of approximately 1950 to 1967. The record group includes minutes of meetings and correspondence and other materials received from the executive director of the Authority, Lawrence Rubin. In addition, there are various reports and audits, including Engineers Construction Progress Reports.
Subjects:
Bridges--Michigan.; Detroit Trust Company.; Mackinac Bridge (Mich.).; Mackinac Bridge Authority (Mich.); Osborn, George A.; Rubin, Lawrence A., 1912-
- Minutes of the Meetings
  - 1950-1967, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Lawrence A. Rubin, Executive Secretary
  - Correspondence with, and other materials, 1950-1965, 3 folders (Box 1)
- Topical Files
  - Refinancing Proposal (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous data (Box 1)
  - Mackinac Bridge dedication festival, June 1958 (Box 1)
  - Proposed Revenue Bonds (Box 1)
  - Reprints of David Steinman articles (Box 1)
- Reports
  - Proposed Mackinac Straits Bridge Preliminary Report, January 10, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Report on Proposed Mackinac Straits Bridge, January 10, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Report on Traffic and Revenues Proposed Mackinac Straits Bridge, January 22, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Supplementary Report on Traffic and Revenues Proposed Mackinac Straits Bridge, August 27, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Report on Traffic and Revenues Proposed Mackinac Straits Bridge, February 3, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Engineering Report on Mackinac Straits Bridge, February 20, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Report on a Study of Rates of Toll on the Mackinac Bridge, May 27, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Engineers Construction Progress Report and Report of Auditors Examination, 5th-16th quarter, 1955-1957 (Box 2)
  - Engineers Construction Progress Report 17th-40th quarter, 1958-1963 (Box 2)
- Financial Reports
  - Financial Statement and Report of Traffic and Revenue
    - November 1957-December 1961 (Box 2)
    - January 1962-December 1966 (Box 3)
  - Report of Examination and Supplementary Data
    - June 1954-September 1955 (Box 3)
  - Audited Financial Statement and Other Financial Information
    - June 1956-December 1966 (Box 3)